A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Penitentiary, 1796-1991 (bulk 1906-1970)
Library of Virginia
- Series VII. Financial Records, 1879-1881, 1884-1980 (bulk 1895-1933)., Extent: 2.69 cubic feet of records and 76 volumes. (Box 687-692., Volume 205-221, 223-254, 256-267, 275-286, 288.)
  - [Account Book, Criminal Expenses (Transportation), November 1906 to October 1922. (Volume 248)
  - Account Book, Trial Balance, June 1914 to March 1920. (Volume 249)
  - Ledger, Guard Expenses, October 1896 to June 1908. (Volume 250)
  - Ledger, Guard Expenses, July 1908 to December 1919. (Volume 251)
  - Ledger, Guard Expenses, January 1920 to March 1933. (Volume 252)
  - Cash Book, January 1884 to December 1899 [in folder]. (Volume 253)
  - Cash Book, July 1906 to September 1918. (Volume 254)
  - Cash Book, July 1911 to September 1921. (Volume 256)
  - Cash Book, July 1924 to May 1926. (Volume 257)
  - [Prisoners'] Cash Book, October 1920 to June 1923. (Volume 258)
  - Cash Book, October 1923 to March 1929. (Volume 259)
  - Cash Book [?] [Received/Paid Out], July 1925 to November 1930 [in folder]. (Volume 260)
  - Cash Register, December 1930 to November 1938. (Volume 261)
  - Cash Book, January 1939 to May 1960. (Volume 262)
  - Cash Book, April 1955 to June 1958. (Volume 263)
  - Cash Book, October 1961 to December 1964. (Volume 264)
  - Cash Book, December 1964 to April 1968. (Volume 265)
  - Monthly Time Book (Penitentiary Guards), February 1914 to September 1916. (Volume 266)
  - Monthly Time Book (Penitentiary Guards), 16 December 1945 to 15 June 1947. (Volume 267)
  - Employee Payroll Book, 1957-1962. (Volume 279)
  - Employee Payroll Book, 1960-1962. (Volume 280)
- Series VIII. Blueprints and Drawings, 1940-1984., Extent: 1.33 cubic feet of records. (Map-case G2)
  The Blueprints and Drawings series is housed in four oversized folders in one map case. Series contains a variety of blueprints and drawings related to improvements or proposed improvements to the Virginia State Penitentiary. This series is not comprehensive. Researchers should search the catalog for other collections containing blueprints and drawings of the Penitentiary.
  - No. 2 - Proposed New Roof and Security Ceiling, Cell Block "A" Building, 27 April 1960, Carl M. Linder and Son (1 sheet). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 2 - Heating System Improvements, Cell Block "A", 1 May 1980, Roach, Merce and Faison, Inc. (5 sheet). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 4 - Maximum Security Building, 25 January 1951, Carneal and Johnston (27 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 11 - Addition to Mezzanine, Woodworking Shop, Industrial Department, April 1958 (27 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 12 - New Boiler House, 29 November 1940, Carneal, Johnston and Wright (2 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 12 - Replacement of Oil Storage Tank, September 1981 (1 sheet). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 14 - Office Building, State Convict Road Force, 25 February 1981 (7 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 15 - Penitentiary Section of Warehouse, November 1950 (1 sheet). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 16 - State Penitentiary and State Convict Road Force, Warehouse, 6 April 1950 (1 sheet). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 17 - Warehouse for Dept. of Welfare and Institutions, Belvidere and Spring Streets, 24 February 1964, Whitmore, Chichester Architects (15 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - No. 18 - Corrections Building, 2 July 1942, Carneal, Johnston and Wright (8 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous - Site Plan/Tunnels and Power House, ca. 1984, Terrence, Dreelin Farthing and Buford, Inc. (9 sheets, 2 copies). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints, New Guard Box, New Wall, Northeast Corner, 7 October 1957 (4 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints, Virginia State Penitentiary, Floor Plan for Cell Building, 22 September 1981, Vincent McKinle (8 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 2)
  - Blueprints, Virginia State Penitentiary, Law Library and Recreation Building, 8 June 1981 (2 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 2)
  - Blueprints, Virginia State Penitentiary, C Building - Maximum Security, undated (3 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 2)
  - Blueprints, Virginia State Penitentiary, undated (17 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 3)
  - Blueprints, Virginia State Penitentiary, Chapel, 23 December 1970 (2 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 3)
  - Blueprints, Virginia State Penitentiary, unidentified building, undated (3 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 3)
  - Blueprints, Guard Quarters, 30 December 1970, DWI School of Drafting (5 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 4)
  - Photostat - Organizational Chart, Dept. of Welfare and Institutions, Division of Corrections, 12 September 1958 (2 copies). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 4)
  - Blueprints - Inmate Holding Area, Medical College of Virginia (MCV) South Hospital Basement, undated (7 sheets). (Map-case G2, Drawer 5, Folder 4)